For more than a year,
ominous rumors had been privately circulating
among high-level Western leaders
that the Soviet Union
had been at work
on what was darkly hinted
to be the ultimate weapon,
a doomsday device.
Intelligence sources traced the site
of the top-secret Russian project
to the perpetually
fog-shrouded wasteland
below the Arctic peaks
of the Zhokhov Islands.
What they were building,
or why it should be located
in such a remote and desolate place,
no one could say.
General Ripper, sir.
Group Captain Mandrake speaking.
- This is General Ripper speaking.
- Yes, sir.
Do you recognize my voice, Mandrake?
I do, sir. Why do you ask?
Why do you think I ask?
Well, I don't know, sir. We spoke just
a few moments ago on the phone, didn't we?
You don't think I'd ask
if you recognized my voice
unless it was pretty damned important,
do you, Mandrake?
- No, I don't, sir, no.
- All right, let's see if we can stay on the ball.
Has the wing confirmed
holding at their fail-safe points?
Yes, sir, the confirmations
have all just come in.
Very well. Now listen to me carefully.
The base is being put on condition red.
I want this flashed
to all sections immediately.
Condition red, sir, yes. Jolly good idea.
Keeps the men on their toes.
Group Captain,
I'm afraid this is not an exercise.
Not an exercise, sir?
I shouldn't tell you this, Mandrake,
but you're a good officer
and you have a right to know.
It looks like we're in a shooting war.
Oh, hell.
- Are the Russians involved, sir?
- Mandrake, that's all I've been told.
It just came in on the red phone.
My orders are for this base to be sealed tight,
and that's what I mean to do, seal it tight.
Now, I want you to transmit plan "R",
"R" for Robert, to the wing.
plan "R" for Robert.
Is it that bad, sir?
- It looks like it's pretty hairy.
- Yes, sir.
plan "R" for Robert, sir.
Now last, and possibly most important,
I want all privately owned radios
to be immediately impounded.
Yes, sir.
They might be used
to issue instructions to saboteurs.
As I previously arranged,
air police will have lists of all owners,
and I want every single one of them
collected without exception.
Yes, sir.
And after you've done that,
report back to me.
Yes, sir.
In order to guard
against surprise nuclear attack,
America's Strategic Air Command
maintains a large force of B-52 bombers,
airborne 24 hours a day.
Each B-52 can deliver
a nuclear bomb load of 50 megatons,
equal to 16 times
the total explosive force
of all the bombs and shells
used by all the armies
in World War II.
Based in America,
the Airborne Alert Force
is deployed from the Persian Gulf
to the Arctic Ocean,
but they have
one geographical factor in common.
They are all two hours
from their targets inside Russia.
Major Kong,
I know you'll think this is crazy,
but I just got a message from base
over the CRM 114,
and it decodes
as Wing Attack plan "R",
"R" for Romeo.
Goldie, did you say
Wing Attack plan "R"?
Yes, sir, I have.
Goldie, how many times
have I told you guys
that I don't want no horsing around
on the airplane?
I'm not horsin' around, sir.
That's how it decodes.
Well, I've been to one world fair,
a picnic and a rodeo,
and that's the stupidest thing
I ever heard come over a set of earphones.
You sure you got today's code?
- Yes, sir, it is.
- There's just gotta be somethin' wrong.
Wait a second. I'm coming back.
Maybe you'd better
get a confirmation from base.
Yes, sir.
Major Kong, is it possible
this is some kind of loyalty test?
You know, give the go code and then
recall to see who would actually go?
Ain't nobody
ever got the go code yet.
And old Ripper
wouldn't be giving us plan "R"
unless them Russkies
had already clobbered Washington
and a lot of other towns
with a sneak attack.
Yes, sir.
Major Kong,
message from base confirmed.
Well, boys, I reckon this is it.
Nuclear combat
toe to toe with the Russkies.
Now, look, boys, I ain't much
of a hand at making speeches,
but I got a pretty fair idea
that something doggone important's
going on back there.
Now, I got a fair idea
of the kind of personal emotions
that some of you fellows may be thinkin'.
Heck, I reckon you wouldn't even
be human beings
if you didn't have some pretty strong
personal feelings about nuclear combat.
But I want you to remember one thing
that folks back home
is a-countin' on ya,
and by golly,
we ain't about to let 'em down.
Tell you something else.
If this thing turns out to be half as
important as I figure it just might be,
I'd say that you're all in line
for some important promotions
and personal citations
when this thing's over with.
And that goes for ever' last one of you,
regardless of your race, color
or your creed.
Now, let's get this thing on the hump.
We got some flyin' to do.
Buck, should I get it?
Yeah, you'll have to.
Hello?
Oh, yes, General Turgidson is here,
but I'm afraid he can't come
to the phone at the moment.
Well, this is his secretary, Miss Scott.
Freddie, how are you?
Fine. And you?
Oh, we were just catching up
on some of the general's paperwork.
Well, look, Freddie,
he's very tied up at the moment.
I'm afraid he can't come to the phone.
Oh, just a minute.
General Turgidson.
A Colonel Puntrich calling.
Tell him to call back.
Freddie, the general says
could you call back in a minute or two?
He says it can't wait.
Aw, for Pete...
Well, find out what he wants.
Freddie, the thing is, the general
is in the powder room right now.
Could you tell me what it's about?
Just a second.
Apparently they monitored a transmission
about eight minutes ago
from Burpelson Air Force Base.
Got it.
It was directed to the 843rd Bomb Wing
on airborne alert.
It decoded as Wing Attack plan "R".
Well, uh, tell him
to call, uh, what's-his-name,
Base Commander Ripper.
Do I have to think of everything?
The general suggests
you call General Ripper,
the 843rd base commander.
All communications are dead.
Bull! Tell him to do it himself.
Freddie, the general asks
if you could possibly try again yourself.
I see.
He says he's tried personally
several times, but everything is dead.
Even the normal phone lines
are shut down.
Give me that.
Fred? Buck.
What's it look like?
Yeah?
Well, are you sure it's plan "R"?
What's cooking
on the threat board?
Nothing? Nothing at all?
I don't like the look of this, Fred.
Tell you what you'd better do,
old buddy.
You'd better give Elmo
and Charlie a blast,
bump everything up to condition red
and stand by the blower.
I'll get back to you.
- What's up?
- Nothin', nothin'.
- Where's my shorts?
- On the floor.
Where are you going?
No place. No place.
I just thought I might, uh, mosey over
to the war room for a few minutes,
see what's doing over there.
- It's 3:00 in the morning.
- Well, the air force never sleeps.
- Buck, honey.
- Yeah?
I'm not sleepy either.
I know how it is, baby.
Tell you what you do.
You just start your countdown,
and old Bucky will be back here
before you can say "blast-off".
Your commie has no regard
for human life,
not even his own,
and for this reason, men,
I want to impress upon you
the need for extreme watchfulness.
The enemy may come individually
or he may come in strength.
He may even come in the uniform
of our own troops.
But however he comes,
we must stop him.
We must not allow him
to gain entrance to this base.
Now, I am going to give you
three simple rules.
First, trust no one,
whatever his uniform or rank,
unless he is known to you personally.
Second,
anyone or anything that approaches
within 200 yards of the perimeter
is to be fired upon.
Third,
if in doubt, shoot first
and ask questions afterwards.
I would sooner accept
a few casualties through accident
than lose the entire base and its personnel
through carelessness.
Any variation on these rules
must come from me personally.
Now, men, in conclusion,
I would like to say
that in the two years it has been my privilege
to be your commanding officer,
I have always expected
the best from you
and you have never given me
anything less than that.
Today the nation is counting on us.
We are not going to let them down.
Good luck to you all.
Here's the attack profile, sir.
This is your attack profile.
To ensure that the enemy
cannot monitor voice transmission
or plant false transmission,
the CRM 114 is to be switched
into all receiver circuits.
The emergency base code prefix
is to be set on the dials of the CRM.
This will block any transmission other
than those preceded by a code prefix.
Stand by to set code prefix.
Roger. Ready to set code prefix.
Set code prefix.
Code prefix set.
Lock code prefix.
Code prefix locked.
Switch all receiver circuits
to CRM discriminators.
All circuits switched
Check auto-destruct circuits.
Auto-destruct circuits checked.
Primary target,
the ICBM complex at Laputa.
Target reference,
Yankee Golf Tango 360.
Thirty-megaton nuclear device
fused for airburst at 10,000 feet.
Twenty-megaton nuclear device
will be used if first malfunctions.
Otherwise,
proceed to secondary target,
missile complex
seven miles east of Barchov.
Target reference,
November Bravo X-ray, 108.
Fused for airburst at 10.
Check. 12,000 feet.
Excuse me, sir.
Something rather interesting
has just cropped up.
Listen to that. Music.
Civilian broadcasting.
I think those fellows in the Pentagon
have given us
some sort of exercise
to test our readiness.
Personally, I think
it's taking things a bit too far.
Our fellows will be inside Russian
radar cover in about 20 minutes.
Listen to that. Chockablock
full of stations all churning it out.
- Mandrake?
- Yes, sir.
I thought I issued instructions
for all radios on this base to be impounded.
Well, you did indeed, sir, and I was
in the process of impounding this very one
when I happened to switch it on.
I thought, our fellows hitting Russian radar
cover in 20 minutes, dropping all their stuff,
I'd better tell you because if they do,
it'll cause a bit of a stink, what?
Group Captain.
The officer exchange program does not
give you any special prerogatives
to question my orders.
Well, I realize that, sir, but I thought
you'd be rather pleased to hear the news.
After all, well, let's face it,
we don't want to start a nuclear war
unless we really have to, do we?
Please sit down.
And turn that thing off.
Yes, sir.
Uh, what about the planes, sir?
Surely we must issue
the recall code immediately.
Group Captain, the planes
are not going to be recalled.
My attack orders have been issued
and the orders stand.
Well, if you'll excuse me
saying so, sir,
that would be, to my way of thinking, rather,
well, a rather odd way of looking at it.
You see, if a Russian attack
was in progress,
we would certainly not be hearing
civilian broadcasting.
- Are you certain of that, Mandrake?
- I'm absolutely positive about that, sir.
And what if it is true?
Well, I'm afraid I'm still not with you, sir,
because, I mean...
If a Russian attack
was not in progress,
then your use of plan "R",
in fact, your orders to the entire wing...
Well, I would say, sir,
that there was something...
dreadfully wrong somewhere.
Now, why don't you just take it easy,
Group Captain,
and please make me a drink
of grain alcohol and rainwater
and help yourself
to whatever you'd like.
General Ripper, sir,
as an officer in Her Majesty's Air Force,
it is my clear duty
under the present circumstances
to issue the recall code
upon my own authority
and bring back the wing.
If you'll excuse me, sir.
I'm afraid, sir, I must ask you
for the key and the recall code.
Have you got them handy, sir?
I told you to take it easy,
Group Captain.
There's nothing anybody
can do about this thing now.
I'm the only person who knows
the three-letter code group.
Then I must insist, sir,
that you give them to me.
Do I take it, sir, that you are threatening
a brother officer with a gun?
Mandrake,
I suppose it never occurred to you
that while we're chatting here so enjoyably,
a decision is being made by the president
and the joint chiefs
in the war room at the Pentagon.
And when they realize there is
no possibility of recalling the wing,
there will be only
one course of action open.
Total commitment.
Mandrake, do you recall what
Clemenceau once said about war?
Uh, no, I don't think I do, sir, no.
He said war was too important
to be left to the generals.
When he said that 50 years ago,
he might have been right.
But today...
war is too important
to be left to politicians.
They have neither the time,
the training
nor the inclination for strategic thought.
I can no longer sit back and allow
Communist infiltration,
Communist indoctrination,
Communist subversion
and the international Communist conspiracy
to sap and impurify
all of our precious bodily fluids.
Staines, is everybody here?
Mr. President,
the secretary of state is in Vietnam,
the secretary of defense is in Laos
and the vice-president is in Mexico City.
We can establish contact with them
at any time if it's necessary.
The undersecretaries
are all here, of course.
Right. Now, General Turgidson,
what's going on here?
Mr. President,
about 35 minutes ago
General Jack Ripper,
the commanding general
of Burpelson Air Force Base,
issued an order
to the 34 B-52's of his wing,
which were airborne at the time
as part of a special exercise
we were holding called Operation Dropkick.
Now, it appears that the order
called for the planes to
attack their targets inside Russia.
The planes are fully armed
with nuclear weapons
with an average load
of 40 megatons each.
Now, the central display of Russia
will indicate the position of the planes.
The triangles are their primary targets.
The squares are their secondary targets.
The aircraft will begin penetrating
Russian radar cover within 25 minutes.
General Turgidson, I find this
very difficult to understand.
I was under the impression
that I was the only one in authority
to order the use of nuclear weapons.
That's right, sir.
You are the only person
authorized to do so.
And although I hate to judge
before all the facts are in,
it's beginning to look like General Ripper
exceeded his authority.
It certainly does, far beyond the point
I would have imagined possible.
Well, perhaps you're forgetting
the provisions of plan "R", sir.
Plan "R"?
Plan "R" is an emergency war plan
in which a lower-echelon commander
may order nuclear retaliation
after a sneak attack
if the normal chain of command
has been disrupted.
You approved it, sir.
You must remember.
Surely you must recall, sir, when
Senator Buford made that big hassle
about our deterrent lacking credibility.
The idea was for plan "R" to be
a sort of retaliatory safeguard.
A safeguard?
Well, I admit the human element
seems to have failed us here.
But the idea was to discourage
the Russkies from any hope
that they could knock out Washington,
and yourself, sir,
as part of a general sneak attack
and escape retaliation because of
lack of proper command and control.
Well, I assume then that the planes
will return automatically
once they reach their fail-safe points.
Well, no, sir, I'm afraid not.
You see, the planes were holding
at their fail-safe points,
when the go code was issued.
Now, once they fly beyond fail-safe,
they do not require
a second order to proceed.
They will continue
until they reach their targets.
Then why haven't you radioed the planes
countermanding the go code?
Well, I'm afraid we're unable to
communicate with any of the aircraft.
Why?
As you may recall, sir,
one of the provisions
of plan "R" provides
that once the go code is received
the normal SSB radios in the aircraft
are switched into
a special coded device
which, I believe,
is designated as CRM 114.
Now, in order to prevent the enemy
from issuing fake or confusing orders,
CRM 114 is designed
not to receive at all
unless the message is preceded by
the correct three-letter code group prefix.
Then do you mean to tell me,
General Turgidson,
that you will be unable
to recall the aircraft?
That's about the size of it, sir.
However, we are plowing through every
possible three-letter combination of the code.
But since there are,
17,000 permutations,
it's going to take us about
two and a half days to transmit them all.
How soon did you say the planes
would penetrate Russian radar cover?
About 18 minutes from now, sir.
- Are you in contact with General Ripper?
- No, sir, no.
General Ripper sealed off the base
and cut off all communications.
Where did you get all this information?
General Ripper called
Strategic Air Command headquarters
shortly after he issued the go code.
I have a portion of the transcript of that
conversation, if you'd like me to read it.
Read it.
The duty officer asked General Ripper
to confirm the fact
that he had issued
the go code and he said...
Yes, gentlemen, they are on their way
and no one can bring them back.
For the sake of our country
and our way of life,
I suggest you get the rest of SAC
in after them.
Otherwise we will be totally
destroyed by Red retaliation.
My boys will give you
the best kind of start,
1,400 megatons worth,
and you sure as hell
won't stop them now.
So let's get going.
There's no other choice.
God willing, we will prevail,
in peace and freedom from fear,
and in true health
through the purity
and essence of our natural...
fluids.
God bless you all.
Then he hung up.
We're still trying to figure out
the meaning of that last phrase, sir.
There's nothing to figure out,
General Turgidson.
This man is obviously a psychotic.
Well, I'd like to hold off judgment
on a thing like that, sir,
until all the facts are in.
General Turgidson, when you instituted
the human reliability tests,
you assured me there was no possibility
of such a thing ever occurring.
Well, I don't think it's quite fair
to condemn a whole program
because of a single slip-up, sir.
I want to speak to General Ripper
on the telephone personally.
I'm afraid that's impossible, sir.
General Turgidson, I am becoming
less and less interested
in your estimates
of what is possible and impossible.
- General Faceman.
- Yes, sir.
Are there any army units
stationed anywhere near Burpelson?
I'll just check, sir.
Hello.
I told you never to call me here.
Don't you know where I am?
Now look, baby,
I can't talk to you now.
My president needs me.
- Of course Bucky would rather be with you.
- What do you think about civil defense?
Why, of course, it isn't only physical.
I deeply respect you
as a human being.
Someday I'm going to make you
Mrs. Buck Turgidson.
All... Listen, hon...
You go back to sleep, hon.
Bucky'll be back there
just as soon as he can.
All right.
Listen, shug, don't forget
to say your prayers.
Apparently,
the 23rd Airborne Division
is stationed seven miles away
at Alvarado.
General Faceman,
I want them to enter the base,
locate General Ripper and put him
in immediate telephone contact with me.
Yes, sir.
Mr. President, if I may advise,
under condition red,
it is standard procedure
that the base be sealed off
and the base defended
by base security troops.
Any force trying to enter there would
certainly encounter very heavy casualties.
General Turgidson, with all due respect
for your defense team,
my boys can brush 'em aside
without too much trouble.
Mr. President, there are one or two points
I'd like to make if I may.
Go ahead, General.
One, our hopes for recalling
the 843rd Bomb Wing
are quickly being reduced
to a very low order of probability.
Two, in less than 15 minutes from now
the Russkies will be making
radar contact with the planes.
Three, when they do
they are gonna go absolutely ape
and they're gonna strike back
with everything they got.
Four, if, prior to this time,
we have done nothing further
to suppress their retaliatory capabilities,
we will suffer virtual annihilation.
Now...
five.
If, on the other hand,
we were to immediately launch
an all-out and coordinated attack
on all their air fields
and missile bases,
we'd stand a damn good chance
of catching them with their pants down.
Hell, we've got a five-to-one
missile superiority as it is.
We could easily assign three missiles
to every target
and still have a very effective reserve force
for any other contingencies.
Now, six,
an unofficial study
which we undertook of this eventuality
indicated that we would destroy 90%
of their nuclear capabilities.
We would, therefore, prevail
and suffer only modest and acceptable
civilian casualties from their remaining force,
which would be badly damaged
and uncoordinated.
General, it is the avowed policy
of our country
never to strike first
with nuclear weapons.
Well, Mr. President, I would say
that General Ripper
has already invalidated that policy.
That was not an act of national policy
and there are still alternatives left open to us.
Mr. President,
we are rapidly approaching
a moment of truth,
both for ourselves as human beings
and for the life of our nation.
Now, truth is not always
a pleasant thing,
but it is necessary now
to make a choice,
to choose between
two admittedly regrettable,
but nevertheless distinguishable
postwar environments,
one, where you got
20 million people killed
and the other where you got
150 million people killed.
You're talking about mass murder,
General, not war.
Mr. President, I'm not saying
we wouldn't get our hair mussed.
But I do say no more than
10 to 20 million killed tops,
depending on the breaks.
I will not go down in history as the greatest
mass murderer since Adolf Hitler.
Perhaps it might be better,
Mr. President,
if you were more concerned
with the American people
than with your image in the history books.
General Turgidson, I think I've heard quite
sufficient from you, thank you very much.
Mr. President, they have
the ambassador waiting upstairs.
Oh, good. Any difficulty?
They say he's having a fit
about that squad of MP's.
Yes, well, that can't be helped.
Have him brought down here straight away.
Yes, sir.
Is that the Russian ambassador
you're talking about?
Yes, it is, General.
Am I to understand
the Russian ambassador
is to be admitted entrance
to the war room?
That is correct.
He is here on my orders.
I don't know
exactly how to put this, sir,
but are you aware of what a serious
breach of security that would be?
I mean, he'll see everything.
He'll see the big board!
That is precisely the idea, General.
That is precisely the idea.
Staines, get Premier Kissoff
on the hot line.
Survival kit contents check.
In them you will find one
.45 caliber automatic,
two boxes ammunition,
four days concentrated
emergency rations,
one drug issue
containing antibiotics,
morphine, vitamin pills, pep pills,
sleeping pills, tranquilizer pills,
one miniature combination
Russian phrase book and Bible,
$100 in rubles,
$100 in gold,
nine packs of chewing gum,
one issue of prophylactics,
three lipsticks,
three pair of nylon stockings.
Shoot, a fella could have a pretty good
weekend in Vegas with all that stuff.
- You don't have any fresh fish?
- I'm afraid not, sir.
- Your eggs then. They are fresh?
- Oh, yes, sir.
I will have poached eggs.
And bring me some cigars, please.
Havana cigars.
- And that will be all for you, sir?
- Yes.
Then I'll see to it right away.
Try one of these Jamaican cigars,
Ambassador. They're pretty good.
Thank you, no. I do not support
the work of imperialist stooges.
Only commie stooges, huh?
Mr. President.
You gonna let that lousy commie punk
vomit all over us like this?
Mr. President, we haven't been able
to reach Premier Kissoff in the Kremlin.
They say they don't know where he is
and he won't be back for another two hours.
- Try B86543, Moscow.
- Yes, sir.
You would never have found him
through his office, Mr. President.
Our premier is a man of the people,
but he is also a man, if you follow my meaning.
- Fine.
- Degenerate atheistic commie.
What did you say?
I said Premier Kissoff
is a degenerate atheistic commie!
Mr. President, I formally request
that you have this ignorant...
I'm sorry, Mr. President.
Mr. President!
I think they're trying the number.
You filthy bully! You filthy brute!
You war-mongering bully!
Gentlemen, you can't fight in here!
This is the war room!
What is going on here?
I demand an explanation.
This clumsy fool tried to plant
that ridiculous camera on me.
Yeah, you bet your sweets, Mr. Commie.
Look at this, Mr. President.
This lousy commie rat was taking pictures
with this thing. Of the big board!
Mr. Ambassador!
This clumsy fool
attempted to plant
that ridiculous camera on me.
That's a damn lie!
I saw him with my own eyes!
Gentlemen, this is outrageous.
I've never heard of such behavior
in the war room before.
Mr. President,
I think they're getting him on the line.
You sure gotta hand it to those commies.
Yeah.
Gee, those trucks sure look like
the real thing, don't they?
I wonder where they got 'em from.
Probably bought them from the army
as war surplus.
Okay, open up at 200 yards.
Tell him where you are and that you'll enter
the conversation if I say anything untrue,
but please don't tell him
anything more than that.
Alexi. Alexi, please, I beg you.
I don't have a phone.
Give him your phone, Frank.
I've done as you asked.
Be careful, Mr. President.
I think he is drunk.
Hello?
Hello, D... Hello, Dmitri.
Listen, I can't hear too well.
Do you suppose you could
turn the music down just a little?
Oh, that's much better.
Yes. Yes.
Fine. I can hear you now, Dmitri.
Clear and plain and coming through fine.
I'm coming through fine too, eh?
Good.
Then...
Well, then as you say,
we're both coming through fine.
Good. Well, it's good
that you're fine and I'm fine.
I agree with you.
It's great to be fine.
Now then, Dmitri,
you know how
we've always talked
about the possibility
of something going wrong
with the bomb.
The bomb, Dmitri.
The hydrogen bomb.
Well, now, what happened is
one of our base commanders,
he had a sort of...
Well, he went
a little funny in the head.
You know, just a little... funny.
And he went and did a silly thing.
Well, I'll tell you what he did.
He ordered his planes...
to attack your country.
Well, let me finish, Dmitri.
Let me finish, Dmitri.
Well, listen,
how do you think I feel about it?
Can you imagine
how I feel about it, Dmitri?
Why do you think I'm calling you?
Just to say hello?
Of course I like to speak to you.
Of course I like to say hello.
Not now, but any time, Dmitri.
I'm just calling up to tell you
something terrible has happened.
It's a friendly call.
Of course it's a friendly call.
Listen, if it wasn't friendly,
you probably wouldn't have even got it.
They will not reach their targets
for at least another hour.
I am positive, Dmitri.
Listen, I've been all over this
with your ambassador. It is not a trick.
Well, I'll tell you.
We'd like to give your air staff
a complete rundown on the targets,
the flight plans
and the defensive systems of the planes.
Yes, I mean, if we are unable
to recall the planes,
then I'd say that,
well, we're just going to have to
help you destroy them, Dmitri.
I know they're our boys.
All right. Well, listen.
Now, who should we call?
Who should we call, Dmitri?
The... What was... The people...
Sorry, you faded away there.
The People's Central Air Defense
headquarters.
Where is that, Dmitri?
In Omsk. Right.
Yes.
Oh, you'll call them first, will you?
Listen, do you happen to have
the phone number on you, Dmitri?
What? I see.
Just ask for Omsk information.
I'm sorry too, Dmitri.
I'm very sorry.
All right, you're sorrier than I am.
But I am sorry as well.
I am as sorry as you are, Dmitri.
Don't say that you're
more sorry than I am,
because I am capable of being
just as sorry as you are.
So we're both sorry, all right?
All right.
Yes, he's right here. Yes, he wants
to talk to you. Just a second.
What?
What is it? What?
The fools.
The mad fools.
What's happened?
The Doomsday Machine.
The Doomsday Machine?
What is that?
A device which will destroy
all human and animal life on earth.
All human and animal life?
Mandrake.
Yes, Jack?
Have you ever seen a commie
drink a glass of water?
Well, no, I...
I can't say I have, Jack.
Vodka.
That's what they drink, isn't it?
Never water.
Well, I...
I believe that's what
they drink, Jack, yes.
On no account
will a commie ever drink water.
And not without good reason.
Oh, yes.
I can't quite...
see what you're getting at, Jack.
Water.
That's what I'm getting at.
Mandrake,
water is the source of all life.
Seven-tenths
of this earth's surface is water.
Why, do you realize that...
70% of you is water?
Oh, how odd.
And as human beings,
you and I need fresh, pure water
to replenish
our precious bodily fluids.
- Yes.
- Are you beginning to understand?
Yes.
Mandrake.
Mandrake, have you
never wondered why
I drink only distilled water,
or rainwater,
and only pure grain alcohol?
Well, I... it did occur to me Jack, yes.
Have you ever heard of a thing
called fluoridation?
Fluoridation of water?
Uh, yes. I have heard of that, Jack.
Yes. Yes.
Well, do you know what it is?
No. No, I don't know what it is, no.
Do you realize
that fluoridation
is the most monstrously conceived
and dangerous Communist plot
we have ever had to face?
Two can play at that game, soldier.
That's nice shooting, soldier!
Mandrake, come here.
Are you calling me, Jack?
Come over here
and help me with this belt.
I...
I haven't had very much experience,
you know,
with those sort of machines, Jack.
I've only ever pressed a button
in my old Spitfire.
Mandrake, in the name of Her Majesty
and the Continental Congress,
come here and feed me this belt, boy.
Jack. I'd love to come, but
what's happened, you see,
the string in my leg's gone.
- The what?
- The string.
I never told you, but you see...
Got a gammy leg.
Oh, dear. Gone, shot off.
Mandrake. Come over here.
The Red Coats are coming. Come on.
When it is detonated, it will produce
enough lethal radioactive fallout
so that within 10 months,
the surface of the Earth
will be as dead as the moon.
Ah, come on, de Sadesky.
That's ridiculous.
Our studies show that even the worst fallout
is down to a safe level after two weeks.
You've obviously never heard
of Cobalt Thorium G.
Well, what about it?
Cobalt Thorium G has
a radioactive half-life of 93 years.
If you take, say, 50 H-bombs
in the hundred megaton range
and jacket them with Cobalt Thorium G,
when they are exploded,
they will produce a doomsday shroud,
a lethal cloud of radioactivity
which will encircle the Earth
for 93 years.
Oh, what a load of commie bull.
I mean, after all...
I'm afraid I don't understand
something, Alexi.
Is the premier threatening to explode this
if our planes carry out their attack?
No, sir.
It is not a thing a sane man would do.
The Doomsday Machine is designed
to trigger itself automatically.
- But surely you can disarm it somehow?
- No.
It is designed to explode if any attempt
is ever made to untrigger it.
- Automatically?
- It's an obvious commie trick, Mr. President.
We're wasting valuable ti...
Look at the big board.
They're getting ready to clobber us.
But this is absolute madness,
Ambassador.
Why should you build such a thing?
There were those of us
who fought against it, but in the end,
we could not keep up with the expense
involved in the arms race,
the space race and the peace race.
And at the same time, our people grumbled
for more nylons and washing machines.
Our doomsday scheme cost us just a small
fraction of what we'd been spending
on defense in a single year.
But the deciding factor
was when we learned that your country
was working along similar lines
and we were afraid
of a doomsday gap.
This is preposterous.
I've never approved of anything like that.
Our source was The New York Times.
Dr. Strangelove, do we have
anything like that in the works?
A moment, please, Mr. President.
Under the authority granted me
as director of weapons research
and development,
I commissioned last year
a study of this project
by the Bland Corporation.
Based on the findings of the report,
my conclusion was that this idea
was not a practical deterrent
for reasons which, at this moment,
must be all too obvious.
Then you mean it is possible
for them to have built such a thing?
Mr. President,
the technology required
is easily within the means
of even the smallest nuclear power.
It requires only the will to do so.
But how is it possible for this thing
to be triggered automatically
and at the same time,
impossible to untrigger?
Mr. President,
it is not only possible,
it is essential.
That is the whole idea
of this machine, you know.
Deterrence is the art of producing
in the mind of the enemy
the fear to attack.
And so, because of the automated
and irrevocable decision-making process
which rules out human meddling,
the Doomsday Machine is terrifying.
Yes, and simple to understand.
And completely credible and convincing.
I wish we had one of them
Doomsday Machines, Stainsey.
But this is fantastic, Strangelove.
How can it be triggered automatically?
Well, it's remarkably simple to do that.
When you merely wish to bury bombs,
there's no limit to the size.
After that, they are connected
to a gigantic complex of computers.
Now then, a specific and clearly defined
set of circumstances
under which the bombs
are to be exploded
is programmed
into a tape memory bank.
- Strangelove.
- A single roll of tape
- can store all the information...
- What kind of a name is that?
That ain't no Kraut name,
is it, Stainsey?
He changed it
when he became a citizen.
It used to be Merkwurdichliebe.
Well, a Kraut by any other name,
Stainsey?
...is that the whole point
of the Doomsday Machine
is lost if you keep it a secret.
Why didn't you tell the world, eh?
It was to be announced
at the Party Congress on Monday.
As you know,
the premier loves surprises.
Stay with me, Mandrake.
All right, Mandrake.
Now feed me, feed me, boy.
Jack, don't you think we'd be better off
in some other part of the room
away from all this flying glass?
We're okay here.
Mandrake.
Do you realize that in addition
to fluoridating water, why,
there are studies under way
to fluoridate salt, flour, fruit juices,
soup, sugar, milk, ice cream?
Ice cream, Mandrake.
Children's ice cream.
Good Lord.
Do you know
when fluoridation first began?
No, no, I don't, Jack.
1946.
1946, Mandrake.
How does that coincide with
your postwar commie conspiracy, huh?
It's incredibly obvious, isn't it?
A foreign substance is introduced
into our precious bodily fluids
without the knowledge of the individual
and certainly without any choice.
That's the way
your hard-core commie works.
Jack, Jack, listen. Tell me.
Tell me, Jack, when did you
first become...
well, develop this theory?
Well, I...
I first became aware of it, Mandrake,
during the physical act of love.
Yes, a profound sense of fatigue,
a feeling of emptiness followed.
Luckily, I was able to interpret
these feelings correctly.
Loss of essence.
Yeah.
I can assure you
it has not recurred, Mandrake.
Women sense my power
and they seek the life essence.
- I do not avoid women, Mandrake.
- No.
But I do deny them my essence.
Yes, Jack.
Cease fire!
The boys must have surrendered.
Well, there it is.
Now, Jack, listen,
while there's still time, I beg you,
let's recall the wing and...
Those boys were like my children,
Mandrake.
Now they've let me down.
No, no, Jack, not a bit of it.
No, I'm sure they all gave
of their very best.
And I'm equally sure they all died
thinking of you...
every man Jack of them... Jack.
Supposing a bit of water has gone off?
Certainly one can never be too sure
about those sort of things.
But you look at me now.
Do I look all rancid and clotted?
You look at me, Jack, eh?
Look, eh?
I drink a lot of water, you know.
I'm what you might call a water man, Jack.
That's what I am.
And I can swear to you, my boy,
swear to you,
that there's nothing wrong
with my bodily fluids.
Not a thing, Jackie.
Mandrake, were you ever
a prisoner of war?
Well, Jack, the time's running very...
- What?
- Were you ever a prisoner of war?
Yes, I was,
as a matter of fact, Jack, I was.
- Did they torture you?
- Yes, they did.
I was tortured by the Japanese,
Jack, if you must know.
- Not a pretty story.
- Well, what happened?
Oh, well, I don't know, Jack.
It's difficult to think of
under these conditions,
but, well, what happened
was they got me on the old
Rangoon-Ichinawa Railway.
I was laying train lines
for the bloody Japanese puff-puffs.
No, I mean,
when they tortured you, did you talk?
No, I... Well, I don't think
they wanted me to talk, really.
I don't think they wanted me
to say anything.
It was just their way of having
a bit of fun, the swines.
The strange thing is
they make such bloody good cameras.
You know, those clowns outside are
gonna give me a pretty good going over
in a few minutes, for the code.
Yes...
Yes, well, you may have...
You may have quite a point there, Jack.
I don't know how well
I could stand up under torture.
Well, of course, the answer to that
is, boy, no one ever does.
And my advice to you, Jack,
is to give me the code now,
and if those devils come back
and try any rough stuff,
we'll fight 'em together, boy,
like we did just now on the floor, eh?
You with your gun, and me with the belt
and the ammo, feeding you, Jack.
"Feed me", you said,
and I was feeding you, Jack.
You know, Mandrake,
I happen to believe
in a life after this one,
and I know I'll have to answer
for what I've done.
And I think I can.
Yes, well, of course you can, Jack.
Of course you can. You can.
I'm a religious man myself,
you know, Jack.
I believe in all that sort of thing,
and I'm hoping you know, Jack.
You've dropped your gun, Jack.
Yes, you know what...
Here. No, Jack, let me take that for you.
I'll take that for you, Jack.
And you know what I'm hoping, Jack?
I'm hoping you're going to give me
the code, boy, that's what I'm hoping.
You're going to have a little wash
and brush up, are you? What a good idea.
Always did wonders for a man that, Jack.
A little wash and brush up.
Water on the back of the neck.
Makes you feel marvelous.
That's what we need, Jack.
Water on the back of the neck and the code.
Supposing I play a little guessing game
with you, Jack boy.
I'll try and guess,
I'll try and guess what the code is.
Copilot to Navigator.
I'm ready with the fuel figures now.
We have 109,000 total,
79,000 in the mains
and 30,000 in the auxiliaries.
And that works out to roughly
seven hours, 15 minutes
endurance for this time.
DSO to Captain.
I have an unidentified radar blip.
Distance, 60 miles.
Approximate speed, Mach 3.
Looks like a missile tracking us.
Confirmed. Definite missile track.
Commence evasive action right.
Missile still closing range.
Distance, 50 miles.
Continue evasive action.
Lock ECM to target intercept mode.
ECM locked to target intercept mode.
Missile still tracking
and closing distance.
Range, 40 miles.
Continue evasive action.
Electronic guidance scrambler
to blue grid.
Missile still tracking steady
and closing distance.
Range, 30 miles.
Missile still closing, true and steady.
Continue evasive action.
Range, 20 miles.
Missile still closing distance
and tracking steady.
Attack range gate on maximum scan.
Range gate on maximum scan.
Range, 10 miles.
Missile track deflecting.
Continue evasive action.
Deflection increasing.
Range, eight miles.
Deflection still increasing.
Range, six miles.
Missile still deflecting.
Range, four miles.
Range, two miles.
Missile still deflecting.
Range, one mile.
Missile detonated.
- Start lever to cut off.
- Cut off.
- Lost engine power.
- Lost power. Got it.
Reselect essential power.
- Oh, shoot. There goes six.
- Essential power reselected.
The hatch is stuck.
- Hit emergency power.
- Okay.
- Extinguishers.
- Roger.
Transfer switches.
- Transferred.
- Push pumps up.
Cut off.
Fuel valves three, four and six.
- Give me full power.
- Roger.
Peace on earth.
POE.
Purity of essence.
OPE.
Put your hands over your head.
What the devil do you think you're doing,
shooting your way in here? Who are you?
I said, put your hands over your head.
What kind of suit
do you call that, fella?
What do you mean, suit?
This happens to be an RAF uniform, sir,
and I am Group Captain Lionel Mandrake.
I am General Ripper's
executive officer.
Where's General Ripper?
He's dead, in the bathroom.
- Where's the bathroom?
- Next to you.
Look, I don't know what sort
of stupid game this is you're playing,
but I've got a very good idea
what the recall code is
and I have to get in touch
with SAC headquarters immediately.
I said put your hands over your head
and keep them there. Come on.
- Got any witnesses?
- Witnesses?
What are you talking about, witnesses?
He shot himself.
While he was shaving?
Now look, Colonel Bat Guano,
if that really is your name,
may I tell you
that I have a very, very good idea,
I think, I hope, I pray,
what the recall code is.
It's some sort of recurrent theme
he kept repeating.
It's a variation on "peace on earth"
or "purity of essence".
- EOP, OPE. It's one of those.
- Put your hands up on top of your head.
Start walkin'.
Don't you know that General Ripper
went as mad as a bloody March hare
and sent the whole wing
to attack the Soviets?
- What are you talking about?
- I'll tell you what I'm talking about.
I'm going to pick up this red telephone,
which is connected to SAC,
and I hope...
Blast. Blast.
Shot away, I expect, by one of your men
during this ridiculous fighting.
Right.
All right, Charlie, I've been
wasting too much time on you.
I've got a lot of wounded men outside.
Start walking.
All the radio gear is out,
including the CRM 114.
I think the auto-destruct mechanism
got hit and blew itself up.
The fire is out.
Emergency power is on.
Everything seems to check out all right.
Will advise.
Roger. Navigator.
I've worked out our rate of fuel loss
at approximately 162 per minute.
This gives us a radius of action
sufficient to take out
primary and secondary targets,
but we will not - repeat -
not be able to make it back
to any base or neutral country.
However, we would have enough fuel
to ditch at weather ship Tango Delta,
grid coordinates 003691.
Well, boys, we got three engines out,
we got more holes in us
than a horse trader's mule,
the radio is gone
and we're leaking fuel,
and if we was flying any lower,
why, we'd need sleigh bells on this thing.
But we got one little budge
on them Russkies.
At this height,
why, they might harpoon us,
but they dang sure ain't gonna
spot us on no radar screen.
The other way.
- Where are you taking me?
- The main gate.
Colonel!
Colonel, I must know what you think
has been going on here.
- You want to know what I think?
- Yes.
I think you're some kind
of deviated "prevert".
And I think General Ripper
found out about your "preversion",
and that you were organizing
some kind of mutiny of "preverts".
Now move.
On top of that, I don't know anything
about any planes attacking Russia.
I was told to get General Ripper on the phone
with the president of the United States.
Now, just one second.
You just said "the president".
What about the president?
Now, the president wants to speak
to General Ripper, doesn't he?
Now, General Ripper is dead,
is he not?
I am General Ripper's executive officer,
so the president will bloody well
want to speak to me, won't he?
There's a telephone box over there
and the line may be open.
You want to talk to the president
of the United States?
I don't want to talk to him, Colonel.
I've got to talk to him.
And I can assure you, if you don't put that
gun away and stop this stupid nonsense,
the Court of Inquiry on this'll
give you such a pranging,
you'll be lucky if you end up wearing
the uniform of a bloody toilet attendant!
Okay. Go ahead.
Try and get the president
of the United States on the phone.
If you try any "preversions" in there,
I'll blow your head off.
Operator?
This is Group Captain Lionel Mandrake.
I'm speaking
from Burpelson Air Force Base.
Look, something very urgent has come up
and I want you to place
an emergency person-to-person call
with President Merkin Muffley
in the Pentagon, Washington, DC.
Burpelson 39180.
No. I'm perfectly serious, Operator.
The president.
Yes, the president
of the United States.
Oh. I'm sorry.
I haven't got enough change.
Could you...
Could you make this
a collect call, Operator?
Just one second, Operator.
They won't accept the call.
Have you got 55 cents?
Well, you don't think I'd go into combat
with loose change in my pocket, do you?
Operator?
Look...
is it possible to make this
an ordinary trunk call?
Well, what do you call it?
You know... Oh, station to station.
Oh, blast! I'm still 20 cents short.
Operator, hold on.
I shan't keep you a second.
Colonel, that Coca-Cola machine.
I want you to shoot the lock off it.
There may be some change in there.
That's private property.
Colonel, can you possibly imagine
what is going to happen to you,
your frame, outlook,
way of life and everything,
when they've learned that you
have obstructed a telephone call
to the president of the United States?
Can you imagine?
Shoot it off! Shoot with a gun.
That's what the bullets are for, you twit!
Okay.
I'm gonna get your money for you.
But if you don't get the president
of the United States on that phone,
- you know what's going to happen to you?
- What?
You're gonna have to answer
to the Coca-Cola company.
This is SAC Communications Control.
The recall code OPE
is being acknowledged "roger"
by the elements of the 843 Bomb Wing.
These are the details.
Missions 12, 22, 30 and 38
are reported destroyed
by enemy action.
All other missions
have acknowledged recall code.
This is SAC Communications Control.
Over and out.
Gentlemen, gentlemen.
Gentlemen.
Mr. President.
I'm not a sentimentalist
at all by nature,
but I think I know
what's in every heart in this room.
I think we ought to
all just bow our heads
and give a short prayer of thanks
for our deliverance.
Lord!
We have heard the wings
of the angel of death
fluttering over our heads
from the valley of fear.
You have seen fit to deliver us
from the forces of evil.
Excuse me, sir.
Premier Kissoff's calling again,
and he's hopping mad.
Fuel flow on active engines
and leakage has increased.
Now works out at 205.
Estimate remaining fuel at 8790.
Roger, confirm 205 per minute
and remaining fuel 8790.
No. No, Dmitri,
there must be some mistake.
No, I'm certain of that.
I'm perfectly certain of that, Dmitri.
Just a second.
You know what he says? He says that
one of the planes hasn't turned back.
He says, according to information
forwarded by our air staffs,
it's headed for the missile complex
at Laputa.
That's impossible, Mr. President.
I mean, look at the big board.
Thirty-four planes. 30 recalls
acknowledged and four splashes,
and one of them
was targeted for Laputa.
Dmitri? Look, we've got
an acknowledgement from every plane
except the four you shot down.
He... Hang on a second, Dmitri.
He says their air defense now
only claims three aircraft confirmed.
The fourth may only be damaged.
Mr. President, I'm beginning
to smell a big fat commie rat.
I mean, supposing Kissoff
is lying about that fourth plane,
just looking for an excuse
to clobber us?
I mean, if the spaghetti hits the fan,
now we're really in trouble.
Dmitri? Look, if this report is true
and the plane manages to bomb the target,
is this... is this going to
is this going to set off
the Doomsday Machine?
Are you sure?
Well, I guess you're just going
to have to get that plane, Dmitri.
Dmitri, I'm sorry they're jamming
your radar and flying so low,
but they're trained to do it.
It's initiative.
Look, Dmitri, you know
exactly where they're going,
and I'm sure your entire air defense
can stop a single plane.
Listen, I mean, it's not gonna
help either one of us
if the Doomsday Machine goes off,
now, is it?
Dmitri, there's no point in you
getting hysterical at a moment like this.
Dmitri, keep your feet on the ground
when you're talking, Dmitri.
I am not... I am not getting...
No, Dmitri, I'm just worried, that's all.
Now look, if our air staff say
its primary target is Laputa
and its secondary target is Barchov,
I mean, it's true, Dmitri,
you've got to believe it.
Look, can I give... Dmitri?
Can I give you just one word...
Can I give you just one word
of advice, Dmitri?
Listen, Dmitri, put everything you've got
into those two sectors and you can't miss.
Sir, if we continue
to lose fuel at the present rate,
I estimate we only have,
38 minutes flying time,
which will not even take us
as far as the primary.
Doggone it, Sweets, you told me
that you'd get me to the primary!
I'm sorry, sir. That estimate was based
on the original loss rate factor,
not at 205.
I don't give a hoot in hell how you do it.
You just get me to the primary, you hear?
I'm sorry, sir, but those are the figures.
We'll be lucky to reach
weather ship at Tango Delta.
Well, shoot!
We ain't come this far
just to dump this thing in the drink.
What's the nearest target of opportunity?
Sir, if the rate of loss does not increase,
we have a chance to reach target 384,
grid coordinate 003691
and possibly make it from there
to the Tango Delta weather ship.
What kind of a target is that anyhow?
Sir, that's the ICBM complex at Kotlas.
All right.
Designating new target 384.
Give me a rough heading on that just as soon
as you can get it worked out, will ya?
Well, we'll keep our fingers crossed,
Dmitri,
and remember, there's just one thing,
we are all in this together.
We're right behind you, Dmitri.
We're with you all the way.
Yes, well, we'll keep the line open.
All right, Dmitri.
General Turgidson, is there really
a chance for that plane to get through?
Mr. President, if I may speak freely,
the Russki talks big, but frankly,
we think he's short of know-how.
You just can't expect
a bunch of ignorant peons
to understand a machine
like some of our boys.
That's not meant as an insult,
Mr. Ambassador.
You take your average Russki,
we all know how much guts he's got.
Hell, look at all them Nazis killed off,
and he still wouldn't quit.
Can't you stick to the point, General?
Well sir,
if the pilot's good, see,
I mean, if he's really sharp,
he can barrel that baby in so low.
You ought to
see it sometime. It's a sight.
A big plane like a 52. Vroom!
Its jet exhaust frying chickens
in a barnyard.
- Yeah, but has he got a chance?
- Has he got a chance?
Hell, yeah... he's...
got a...
Navigator to Captain.
Approaching target
at distance 10 miles.
Switch from green grid
to target orange.
Roger.
Ready for final bomb run check.
- Take over, Ace.
- Roger.
- DSO ready.
- Bombardier ready, sir.
Bomb fusing master safety on.
Electronic barometric time
and impact.
Bomb fusing, master safeties on,
electronic barometric time and impact.
Fuse for ground burst.
Delay factor yellow three.
Bomb fusing circuits
one through four test.
Lights on.
Bomb arming test lights on
one through four.
Engage primary
trigger switch override.
Primary trigger switch
override engaged.
Track indicators to maximum deflection.
Detonator set to zero altitude.
Release first safety.
First safety released.
First safety.
Release second safety.
Second safety released.
Second safety.
Check bomb door circuits
one through four.
Bomb door circuits
negative function.
Lights red.
- Switch in back-up circuits.
- Roger.
Back-up circuits switched in.
Still negative function.
Engage emergency power.
Roger.
Emergency power on.
Still negative function.
Operate manual override.
Roger.
Still negative function.
The Teleflex drive cable
must be sheared away.
Fire the explosive bolts!
Roger.
Still negative, sir.
The operating circuits are dead, sir.
Stay on the bomb run, Ace.
I'm going down below and see what I can do.
Roger.
Stay on the bomb run, boys.
I'm gonna get them doors open
if it harelips everybody on Bear Creek.
Target range grid reference checks.
Target distance, eight miles.
Roger. Eight miles.
Telemetric guidance computer
into orange grid.
Target distance, seven miles.
Correct track indicator minus seven.
Roger. Seven miles.
Check GPI acceleration factor.
GPI acceleration factor set.
Target distance, six miles.
Roger. Six miles.
Pulse indent transponder active.
Target distance, five miles.
Five miles.
Homing alignment factor to zero mode.
Target distance, four miles.
Roger. Four miles.
Auto CDC into manual Teleflex link.
Target distance, three miles.
Roger. Three miles.
Target in sight!
Where in hell is Major Kong?
Hey, what about Major Kong?
Mr. President.
I would not rule out the chance to preserve
a nucleus of human specimens.
It would be quite easy.
At the bottom of some
of our deeper mine shafts.
The radioactivity would never penetrate
a mine some thousands of feet deep.
And in a matter of weeks,
sufficient improvements in dwelling space
could easily be provided.
How long would you have to
stay down there?
Well, let's see now...
Cobalt Thorium G.
Radioactive half-life of...
I would think that possibly...
100 years.
You mean, people could actually
stay down there for a hundred years?
It would not be difficult, mein Fhrer.
Nuclear reactors could...
I'm sorry, Mr. President.
Nuclear reactors could provide power
almost indefinitely.
Greenhouses could maintain plant life.
Animals could be bred and slaughtered
A quick survey would have to be made
of all the available mine sites in the country,
but I would guess that...
dwelling space for several hundred thousands
of our people could easily be provided.
Well, I would hate to have to decide
who stays up and who goes down.
Well, that would not
be necessary, Mr. President.
It could easily be accomplished
with a computer,
and the computer could be set
and programmed
to accept factors from youth, health,
sexual fertility, intelligence,
and a cross section
of necessary skills.
Of course, it would be absolutely vital
that our top government
and military men be included
to foster and impart
the required principles
of leadership and tradition.
Naturally, they would breed
prodigiously?
There would be much time
and little to do.
But with the proper breeding techniques
and a ratio of, say,
10 females to each male,
I would guess that they
could then work their way back
to the present gross national product
within, say, 20 years.
But look here, Doctor,
wouldn't this nucleus of survivors
be so grief stricken and anguished
that they'd...
well, envy the dead
and not want to go on living?
And also... Excuse me.
Also, when they go down into the mine,
everyone would still be alive.
There will be no shocking memories,
and the prevailing emotion will be
one of nostalgia for those left behind,
combined with a spirit of bold curiosity
for the adventure ahead.
Doctor,
you mentioned the ratio
of 10 women to each man.
Now, wouldn't that necessitate
the abandonment
of the so-called monogamous
sexual relationship?
I mean, as far
as men were concerned?
Regrettably, yes.
But it is, you know, a sacrifice required
for the future of the human race.
I hasten to add that since each man
will be required to do prodigious...
service along these lines,
the women will have to be selected
for their sexual... characteristics,
which will have to be
of a highly stimulating nature.
I must confess, you have
an astonishingly good idea there, Doctor.
Thank you, sir.
I think we ought to look at this from
the military point of view. I mean...
supposing the Russkies stashed away
some big bombs, see, and we didn't.
When they come out in a hundred years,
they could take over.
I agree, Mr. President.
They might try an immediate sneak attack
so they could take over our mine shaft space.
Yeah. I think it would be
extremely naive of us, Mr. President,
to imagine that these new developments
are going to cause any change
in Soviet expansionist policy.
I mean, we must be
increasingly on the alert
to prevent them from taking over
other mine shaft space
in order to breed more prodigiously
than we do,
thus knocking us out through
superior numbers when we emerge.
Mr. President,
we must not allow a mine shaft gap!
Sir, I have a plan.
Mein Fhrer,
I can walk!